未來
The future
兩極冰蓋融化
The polar ice caps have melted,
地球被淹沒在海洋中
covering the Earth with water.
倖存者逐漸適應了這個...
Those who survived have adapted...
新世界
to a new world.
水  世  界
我沒上你船
我不會幹那種事
你潛水很長時間了
我在修船
船破了個大洞  有空間讓我呼吸
你真倒霉
Bad luck, English.
奴隸販子正在做合成松香
But the Slavers are producing a good grade of poxy these days.
跟你換一半泥土  風鈴也許
Cost you a handful of dirt... or maybe that wind chime.
-你在這裡做什麼?  -等生意
-What are you doing here? -Just waiting.
別碰船帆
Take your hand off the sail.
我說別碰
Take it off!
我看過你的船  沒見過你
I've seen your boat before. Haven't seen you.
這可是合法的
Took it legal.
我發現這艘船時  主人早死了
Previous owner was dead on the tiller when I found it.
你考慮一小時  不然我就找別人
You had another hour before I traded up again.
我得替我自己打算
Just improving my means.
-算我欠你個人情  -不用了
-Well, I owe you then. -No, thanks.
我剛離開一個環礁  給養很充足
I got all the supplies I need. Just came from an atoll.
想去就往東走八天航程
Eight days east, if you're interested.
-浪人碰面通常都要交換些東西  -我知道規矩
-Two drifters meet, something needs to be exchanged. -I know the code.
但這次免費
But I'll give you this one for free.
水世界沒免費的東西
Nothing's free in Waterworld.
機動人
Smokers.
風勢夠我從容開溜
Just enough wind to get away clean.
別管那玩意了
Forget the bag.
不值得  想跑就快升帆吧
It's not worth it. You'll never make it with your sails down.
算你倒霉
What can I say?
-喬  他要去搶那東西  -搞什麼鬼?
-Joe, he's going for it. -What the hell?
沒見過這玩意
Never seen that before.
上呀  衝呀
Here we go! Go! Drive! Drive!
快點  快點
Faster! Faster!
快點  要被他搶走了
Come on! He's gonna get it! He's gonna get it!
-快逮他  -快啊
-Pick her up! -Get it! Get it!
不
Oh, no!
有船來  大門前方
Inbound! Straight out from the gates.
你講什麼話?
英語
English.
別升旗了  今天不交換東西
Flag's down, drifter. We got enough traders.
他拿的是什麼?
What he got?
泥土
Dirt.
開門
Open the gates!
屍體長果子
Bones to berries.
血脈變蔓籐
Veins to vine.
肢骨化為大樹  血漿變鹽水
These tendons to trees. This blood to brine.
她衰老而死
Too old she was.
這女人離我們而去  被引領我們的...
This woman does leave us, recycled and enshrined...
上帝收回
in the presence of Him who leads us.
那是什麼?
What is that?
認識我嗎?
You know me?
我知道你
I know what you are.
你知道  要是你在這惹麻煩
Good. Then you know if you look for trouble while you're here,
你就會吃不了兜著走
You』ll find more than you can handle.
你有兩個小時
You got two hours.
我只需要一小時
I'll only need one.
他過來了
He's coming over here.
-給我  -每人一個...
-Me. -You each get one...
但要幫我看好船
if everything's here when I get back.
很純的泥土
Pure dirt.
3.2公斤
3.2 kilos.
哪兒找的這麼多泥土?
How'd you come by so much of it?
向西30個水平線的環礁
Another atoll 30 horizons west of here.
他們從哪兒拿來的?
Where'd they get it?
-他們沒說  -聽說那地方的人...
-They didn't say. -We heard about that place...
都被殺光了...
that they was all killed.
-所以他們才沒說  -機動人幹的?
-That's why they didn't say. -Smokers?
也許是機動人  也許是奴隸販
Maybe Smokers, maybe Slavers.
值多少?  想交換嗎?
So what's the word? We trading or not?
我們就用乾淨的淡水計算
We'll tally it like, uh, pure hydro.
換給你62份
Works out to... 62 chits.
我要加倍
I want twice that.
-我想喝口水  -除非你告訴我
-I just want one sip of hydro! -No, not till you tell me.
她背上有圖案  我看過
She got inkings on her back. I seen her.
聽說  如果能讀懂那小孩背上的符號
They say if you read the marks on the child,
你就能找到陸地
they'll lead ya all the way to Dryland.
-陸地只是神話  -可有人想信
-Dryland's a myth. -Some still believe.
他們還說機動人  也在找這小女孩
They say the Smokers even got an eye out for her.
那我們最好保守秘密
Well, then, we'd better keep it to ourselves.
能幫你嗎?
Help you?
-商店在哪裡?  -這裡就是
-Where's the store? -You found it.
沒什麼東西
You don't have much.
你就是帶泥土來的人?
You the man with the dirt?
敬一杯
Skoal.
-再來一杯  -兩杯
-One more. -Make it two.
你這麼有錢應該請客吧
A man this rich will buy for a fellow outwater, I'm sure.
一杯
One.
你這雙靴子真不錯
That's an interesting pair of boots you got.
-想換嗎?  -不
-Trade?  -No.
可惜
Shame.
伊諾雅  你在幹什麼?
Enola. Hey, what are you doing?
-不行  -我要再拿一塊去畫畫
-No, you can't do that. -I need another piece. I want to draw some more.
我拿給你  快到後面去
I'll get it to you. Just stay in the back.
你有這麼多水  你可以洗澡了
With all those chits, you could order up a bath.
-你用清水洗過澡嗎?  -你為什麼找我說話?
-Have you ever had a freshwater bath? -Why are you talking to me?
只想交個朋友
Just being friendly.
-那是蕃茄樹嗎?  -對
-Is that a tomato plant? -Yeah.
好眼力
You have a keen eye.
我在圖上看過  多少錢?
Saw one in a picture. How much?
你一半的錢
Half your chits.
-那些我也要  -還要什麼?
-I'll take them too. -Take what?
-你都買光了  -我要那架子
-You bought everything. -I'll take them shelves.
這十五個月你都看到些什麼?
So, what did you see out there in your 15 months?
-比如說?  -海水的盡頭
-Such as? -An end to all this water.
你問錯人了
Asking the wrong person.
今天埋葬了一個人?
The one they buried today?
這裡就是她的盡頭
She found the only end there is.
航海人  我有個提議
I've got a proposition for you, Mariner.
-我不會留下來  -我們沒要你留下來  我們只要你的種
-I'm not staying. -We're not asking you to. All we want is your seed.
找自己人讓她懷孕也行
We can look to our own for impregnation,
只是這樣子生下的孩子  不是很好
but too much of that sort of thing gets... undesirable.
當她懷孕後  你就能走了...
When she's pregnant, you go on your way...
你想要什麼就拿什麼
with all the supplies you need.
你們一無所有  快絕種了
You don't have anything. You're dying.
單身航海這麼久  不該拒絕女人
No man stays out that long and turns down a woman.
-他一定在隱瞞什麼  -也許是機動人間諜
-He's hiding something. -Maybe he's a Smoker spy.
長老讓你走  你才能走
When the elders say so, you can leave,
要不然甭想離開
and not before.
鰓
Gills.
-變種人  -他是變種人
-Mutation! -He's a mutant!
我的手
My hand!
快撒網
Throw the nets!
你憑什麼...
By what right...
你請我來維持和平
You pay me to keep the peace.
這不算和平
This isn't it.
-他殺了我們一個人  -他只是自衛
-He has killed one of ours. -He was defending himself.
-我們要消滅他  -宰了他
-He needs to be destroyed! -Kill him. Let's kill him.
也許吧  但不能就這樣隨便殺人
That may be, but not here and not like this.
那是什麼?
What is it?
太緊了  打不開
It's tight. I can't get it off.
開門
Open the gate.
那是地圖嗎?
Is it a map?
伊諾雅  知道就跟我說  好嗎?
You'd tell me if you knew, wouldn't you, Enola?
-你在畫什麼?  -不知道
-What are you drawing? -I don't know.
海倫  你看  看這小天才的最新幻想
Helen, look. Look at the prodigal child's latest vision.
-我們什麼時候能走?  -我還不知道去哪兒呢
-How soon before we can leave? -I don't have any idea yet where we can go.
我還沒弄懂她的紋身
I haven't figured out the tattoo on her back.
我很蠢  答案就在眼前
I'm a stupid man. The answer's right there.
我卻搞不懂
It's just beyond me.
也許他知道
Maybe he knows.
我看得出來  那是蹼
Oh, yes, I see. They are webbed.
1  2  3  4...  有10個趾頭  太棒了
One, two, three, four... ten digits. That's wonderful.
他們說你有鰓
They tell me, too, that you have gills.
放射狀的鰓  他們只是痕跡  還是真的有用?
Isotropic gills. Are they merely vestigial or are they functional now?
我叫葛雷格  我來看看你...
My name is Gregor. I've just come to pay you a little...
真是的
Oh, my God.
抱歉  我不是笑你
I'm sorry. I'm not laughing at you.
我很興奮  你的鰓真能用
I'm excited. Your gills. They're functional.
你是魚人  你能在水裡呼吸
Ichthyic sapien. You can breathe in the water.
你能潛多深?  我來只是...
How deep can you go? Look, I'm only here...
因為我想多瞭解你
because I want to learn more about you.
你不太喜歡人類  是吧?
You don't like humans very much, do you?
我也不怪你  告訴我
I can't say that I blame you. But tell me:
你的同類脾氣都那麼壞嗎?
Are all of your kind as bad-tempered as you are?
-我沒有同類  -胡說
-I have no "kind." -Oh, fish rot.
你肯定還有同類  就算現在沒有
I'd be surprised if there weren't others, and if there aren't,
最終也會有的
there will be eventually.
我來是要問你一個問題
Anyway, I've come here because I need to ask you a question.
你的泥土從哪兒來的?
Where... Where did your dirt come from?
從陸地來的嗎?
Is it from Dryland?
你知道這是什麼嗎?
Do you know what this is?
古時候的人做了壞事
The ancients... They did something terrible, didn't they?
幾百年前他們導致了這場大水
To cause all this water. Hundreds... Hundreds of years ago.
如果我說  你肯開鎖嗎?
If I tell you, will you open this lock?
我沒鑰匙
I haven't a key.
-用防滑釘開鎖  -什麼?
-There's a mooring cleat down there. -What?
-能當鑰匙用  -防滑釘?
-Good as any key. -A mooring cleat?
我不會傷人  我只想離開
I won't hurt anyone. I'll just leave.
-我馬上回來  -葛雷格
-I'll be right back. -Gregor!
你在那裡幹什麼?
What's your business there?
-快走吧  -我膽子很小
-Move along! -I'm not a brave man.
要是你有陸地的消息  請跟我說
If you know anything about Dryland, please tell me. Please!
求你別把秘密帶進棺材
Don't let it die with you.
別這樣
No, no, no, no. Stop!
葛雷格  快走
Gregor! Move along!
經過慎重考慮證據之後
After considerable deliberation of the evidence at hand,
我們認為這變種人...
it is our decision that this mute-o...
對我們構成威脅
does, indeed, constitute a threat.
因此為了公共安全
Therefore, in the interest of public safety,
我在此判決  依照慣例...
he is hereby sentenced to be recycled...
將他處死
in the customary fashion.
行刑
Proceed.
對不起
I'm sorry.
屍體長果子
Bones to berries.
血脈變蔓籐
Veins to vines.
肢骨化為大樹  血漿變鹽水
His tendons to trees. His blood to brine.
和以往不一樣的生活
Too strange for life he was.
這個變種人離我們而去
This mute-o now does leave us,
被引領我們的...
recycled and entombed...
上帝收回
in the presence of Him who leads us.
機動人  東邊
Smokers! Dead out of the sun!
大家各就各位
To your posts!
-殺  -那裡
-Kill! -There!
在城牆內很安全
We are safe behind these walls.
是吧?
Aren't we?
放我出來
Let me out!
讓我幫忙
Let me out! I'll fight!
給我拿下這座城
Give me the key to the city now.
出發  開始
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
加速  加速
Floor it! Floor it! Floor it!
快擦槍
Swab it! Swab it!
把門撞開
Break down the door!
天哪
My God!
這環礁快是我們的了
We'll have this atoll in no time.
快搖  快搖
Crank it! Crank it!
看!
Look!
小心
Look out!
糟糕
Oh, no!
快加油
You get that going! Fill them up!
海倫  快來
Helen, come quickly!
海倫
Helen!
還不能走呀
You're not supposed to go yet!
可惡的機器
Infernal machine!
葛雷格  等等
Gregor. Gregor, wait!
海倫  我在想辦法  這是意外  停不下來
Helen, I tried. There was an accident. I can't make it stop. Hurry!
快上來  走樓梯  快點
You can make it if you try. Run! Up those stairs. Run! Quickly!
快點  我把繩子丟給你
I'll throw you a rope. Run quickly!
-把繩子丟下來  -等等
-Throw the rope now. Run, Enola. -Slow down! Wait!
-Throw the rope. No! No! -Wait!
-別丟下我們  -不
-Gregor, don't leave us! -Oh, no!
對不起  這是意外
I'm sorry! It was an accident!
海倫  伊諾雅  對不起
Helen! Enola! Helen, I'm sorry!
打下來
Shoot him. Shoot him.
我把你放了  你要帶我們走
If I let you out of here, you're taking us with you.
好
Sure.
伊諾雅  蹲下
Enola, get down.
這邊  蹲下
Here. Get over here. Get down.
快點
Hurry! Come on!
去開大門
Get the gate.
快點
Hurry up!
神風隊  衝呀
Kamikazes. Come on!
炸了個洞
That made a hole.
去抓小女孩
Find her! Get the girl!
在那裡
There!
逮住那傢伙
Go get that guy! Go! Kill him!
-你太慢了  -到另一邊去
-You're too slow! -Run to the other side.
快呀
Come on!
抓緊...
Grab on! Hold on, hold on.
卡住了  我出不去
I'm stuck! I can't make it through!
放開
Let her go!
讓她下來
Just drop her!
快去推齒輪  快推齒輪
Turn the wheel. The wheel! Turn it!
這個  快呀  快推
That! Come on! Push it!
-我在推  -用力拉
-I am! -Hurry! Now pull!
用力推...
Push it! Push it hard! Push it hard!
拉這個...
Okay, okay! Now pull this! Pull this!
拉啊...
Pull! Pull it! Hurry!
伊諾雅  跳
Enola, jump.
別看我  快跳
Don』t Look at me. Jump! Now!
我說過  還沒打完就能開溜嗎?
Well, excuse me! Did I say anybody could leave before the battle was over?
-說過嗎  -沒有
-Did I? -No! No!
那就快干  我恨帆船
Well, do something. I hate sails.
嘿  你會開船嗎?
Hey! Can you steer?
能相信你嗎?
Can I trust you?
誰能告訴我  這艘船為什麼還在開火?
Answer me this, somebody. Why is that boat still firing?
-那兄弟叫什麼?  -查克
-What's that cousin's name? -Chuck.
-查克  -他把船拉向我們
-Hey, Chuck! -He's pulling him right into us.
他沒反應  叫他查爾理試試
Maybe he doesn't answer to "Chuck." Call him "Charles." Charles!
快阻止他  快呀
Stop him! Stop him!
查爾理
Charles!
再見  表兄
Adios, cousins.
她一定在這裡  繼續找
She's here somewhere. Keep looking.
住手
Stop it!
-有什麼收穫?  -幾個小角色  什麼都不知道
-What you got? -Couple of heartbeats over there. Aren't saying much.
如果你注意到  我的血順著我頭上的洞流出來
If you'll notice the arterial nature of the blood coming from the hole in my head,
你就知道我今天很不爽
you can assume that we're all having a real lousy day.
現在我直說  我要找紋身女孩
So here it is: I need to know about that tattooed girl.
誰先說  誰活命
First one that tells me lives.
-我看到了女孩  -她身上有紋身
-I saw a girl. I saw, I saw... -It was... She had a big tattoo on her.
你贏了  重新來
You won. Start over.
我看到了這小女孩
I saw a girl. I'm not sure,
她好像上了那艘三體船
but I think she got on that boat with three hulls.
我想她就是上了那艘雙體船
But I think she got on that boat with three hulls.
-那艘讓我損失慘重的船  -對  變種人的船
-The boat that cost me a thousand G's of go-juice? -Yeah, the mute-o's boat.
-變體人?  -他這裡有裂口
-Mute-o? -Yeah. He got these slits here.
就像魚的鰓
Like...  Like fish gills.
其實他不是人
He wasn't really a man.
進化的突變
A fluke of evolution.
對不起  突變...
Oh, I'm sorry. A fluke of, uh...
-進化  -我知道
-Evolution. -I know!
-不  你說過不會殺我  -我說過嗎?
-No! No, you said you wouldn't kill me! -Did I say that?
-誰聽見我說過?  -對  對  你說...
-Witnesses, anybody, did I? -Yes, yes, yes! You said...
-你說過  -也許是吧
-You said it. -Oh, I may have.
也許吧
I may have.
我們回帝斯號吧
We get to the Deez,
快派飛機出去巡邏
Take up that sky boat; send it out on patrol.
我們要留意...
We gotta keep an eye out...
那個怪物
for that ichthyic-freak.
你到過那兒  對吧?
You been there, haven't you?
陸地?
Dryland?
你知道在哪裡
You know where it is.
對  我知道
Yeah, I know where it is.
我們要去嗎?
And, uh... And we're going?
你和我去
You and I are.
我們要把孩子丟下船
The kid we gotta pitch over the side.
-什麼  -我的船受損
-What? -My boat's tore up.
開始進水
I'm taking on water.
我只有一半的淡水了
I'd be lucky to get half a hydro ration out of that.
你知道...  我可以不喝
You know... I said I won't drink.
十二天?
For 12 days?
最好你們其中一個現在就去死...
No. It's better one of you dies now...
免得你們一起死
than both of you die slow.
等等
Wait. Wait.
我們放你出來  救了你一命
We saved your life. We got you out.
你救了我  但你也逃出來了  大家互不相欠
No, you got me out so you could get out. We're even.
她會煮菜  抓魚
She can cook. She can fish.
-我也會  -我給你項鏈
-So can I. -Then take my necklace. Take my necklace.
-我下面有更好的  -不  聽著
-I got better ones below. -No, look!
我理解你在城裡的遭遇
After what you went through back there on the atoll,
我也理解你的想法
I can understand why you would want to.
可是她只是孩子
But she's a child.
你還想要別的?
Is there something else then?
伊諾雅  下去
Enola! Go below.
伊諾雅
Enola.
你說你...
Yeah. You said so yourself...
出海很久了
Been out there a long time.
幾小時前  你們想把我變成泥土
Couple hours ago, I was potential dirt to you.
-我們不是那種人  -你們都一樣
-We're not like that. -You all are.
你知道我是怎麼想嗎?
Know what I was really thinking?
我為什麼不現在把你們丟下船
Why I don't drop both of you in my wake right now.
我不需要你們
You got nothing I need.
把我們帶到陸地
You're taking us to Dryland.
殺人並不容易
Killing's a hard thing to do well.
-殺我更不簡單  -我也一樣
-Believe me. I'm not the one to start on. -Both of us!
你打算指著我多久?
How long you plan to hold that on me?
多久都行
As long as it takes.
-好吧  -不
-Okay. -No!
讓我出來
Let me out of here!
你在哪  別碰我孩子
Where the hell are you? Don't you touch my child.
過來
Come here!
你別動  這裡
Okay, now don't move, okay? There.
看來不錯
Oh, looking real good, yeah.
行了
There. There.
弄好了
All done.
視野可能會有點小問題
Now, there may be some small problem in depth perception.
最好別影響我開槍
Well, it better not screw up my short game.
-怎麼樣?  -看起來不錯
-Well? -Looks good. I like it. Yeah.
-比你真的眼睛好看  -好看多了
-I like it better than your real eye. -Much better.
-你覺得呢  多碧?  老實說  -像狗屎
-What do you say, Toby? The truth. -Looks like shit.
我就喜歡孩子  率直
That's why I love children. No guile.
真的像狗屎
It does look like shit.
像冰狗屎
And it feels like cold shit!
帝剛...
Deacon? What...
對不起  油坑裡有點問題
I'm sorry. It』s just that there's a problem in the pit.
也許你該去看看
Maybe you should come.
咱們飆車吧
Let's drive.
去油坑  別看風景
The pit. Don't bother with the scenic route.
開車
Drive!
開起來更順手了
Hey, it's driving better.
讓開
Get off!
閃開  讓路
Get over there. Get out of the way.
好了  好...
All right, all right, all right. Okay, okay.
你們很棒  各位表兄  祝你們好運
You guys are great. Bless all you cousins over there.
繼續努力  有成長就有進步
Keep up the good work. Growth is progress. Growth is progress.
有人嗎?
Somebody! Hey, up there!
開蓋子
Take it off!
-什麼事?  -帝剛大人
-Yes. -Your Deaconship.
早安  還是晚安
Hello. Good morning. Or night,
隨便啦
whichever the case may be.
-有什麼事?  我是大忙人  -我應該讓你知道
-What is it? I'm a busy man. -I thought you should know.
我們還有...
We're down to exactly...
四英尺  九英吋深的黑東西了
four feet, nine inches of black stuff.
謝謝你
Thank you, sir.
-還能煉出多少油?  -也許三艘加油船
-How many G's is that after refining? -Maybe three refuelers.
-還夠用兩個月  -老天
-We'll burn through that in two lunars. -Sweet Joe!
有人告訴我這出了什麼問題?
Will somebody please tell me what's happened to this place?
這裡人太多了
We outgrowed it.
現在最重要的是  找到紋身女孩
All right, the only thing that is important is the tattooed girl.
為了找她我們不能省油
We don't spare any go-juice finding her.
別的地方就別浪費  馬上停止牽引機...
We don't waste it anywhere else. You cancel all those tractor pulls...
和其他機器
and all that stuff until later.
你明白嗎?
You got it?
陸地就是樂土
Dryland is the mother lode.
加把勁
On your toes.
太好了
Excellent.
-嗨  -閃開
-Hi. -Move.
伊諾雅  過來
Enola! Enola, come here!
過來
Come on!
伊諾雅  過來
Enola, come over here.
-你在幹什麼?  -裝飾你的船  它好醜
-What are you doing? -Decorating your boat. It's ugly.
-你從哪兒拿來的?  -下面
-Where did you get this? -From down below.
這是我的  我的東西不能碰
This is mine! You don't touch anything of mine.
-我是為了你畫的  -別到處亂畫  明白嗎?
-I drew it for you. -You don't draw on anything. You understand?
什麼...
What...
這是我的船  我喜歡這樣子
This is my boat. I got it the way I like it.
你們佔了空間  減慢了速度
You take up space and you slow me down.
她只是個小女孩
You know, she's just a little girl.
-她不懂規矩  -想留下來嗎?
-She doesn't know your rules. -You wanna stay?
就去教教她
You teach her.
伊諾雅  我是怎麼說的?
Enola, what'd I tell you?
你沒那麼狠  知道嗎?
You're not so tough. You know that?
你殺過多少人?
How many people have you killed?
十個?  二十個?
Ten? Twenty?
-你話太多  -那是因為你不講話
-You talk a lot. -I talk a lot cause you don't talk at all.
多少人?
Now how many?
-包括小女孩?  -我才不怕你
-Including little girls? -I'm not afraid of you.
我跟海倫說   你剪短髮沒那麼醜
I told Helen you wouldn't be so ugly if you cut your hair.
你在旁邊嘮叨
In fact, you talk all the time.
-好像颱風一樣  -伊諾雅
-It's like a storm when you're around. -Enola!
嘿  你幹什麼?
Hey! What are you doing?
-你這渾蛋  -她不會游泳
-Helen! -You bastard! She can't swim!
海倫  救我
Help me! Helen!
海倫  快來救我
Helen, help me!
海倫
Helen!
海倫  救我
Helen, help me!
海倫
Helen! Helen!
撐著點
Hold on!
看著我  看著我
Look at me. Look at me. Look at me.
求求你  回來
Oh, please, come back. Please!
求求你
Please! Oh, please!
撐住  快了...
Hold on. Okay, almost...
謝謝  我發誓
Thanks. I swear,
你敢再碰她...
if you ever touch her again...
渾蛋  看著我
You son of a bitch. Look at me.
你上床以後就會一睡不醒
You will go to bed that night, and you will never wake up.
-閉嘴  -什麼?
-Shut up. -What?
-機動人  -對
-Smokers? -Yeah.
我們能跑掉嗎?
Can't we outrun them?
沒拉帆不行
Not with my sail down.
-你在幹什麼?  -運氣不錯
-What are you thinking about? -That's a nice touch.
他們在那裡
That's them.
別打到那孩子
Don't hit the kid.
懦夫
Coward!
媽的
Fuck!
住手
No!
砍斷
Cut it!
快啊
Come on! Come on!
真是抱歉
Oh, I'm really sorry.
真抱歉  你讓我別無選擇
I'm sorry. But you didn't give me much choice.
我知道
Oh, I know.
但你開溜了
But you ran away. L... What?
你幹什麼?  別這樣
What are you do... No! Please, no! No!
別碰我船上的東西
Don't ever touch anything on my boat again.
她說她很抱歉
She said she was sorry!
所以你也得說點好話
That means you're supposed to say something back!
你在說話嗎?
Did you say something?
那小女孩和他在一起嗎?
The child... did he have the girl with him?
如果我們現在出發
Seems to me if we launch now,
就能在這裡截住他
we can cut him down just about here.
-要是他沒改變航道的話  -應該不會
-If he doesn't change course. -Ah, it's not likely.
那個魚怪挺聰明的
He's a wily one, that ichthyic-demon.
他只要知道自己被盯上
Yeah, if he knows he's been spotted,
就會想  我們會猜他改航道
he'll expect us to expect him to change course,
所以他不會改航道
which is exactly why he'll keep his heading.
問題是他要上哪兒
The important question is, where's he heading?
他知不知道船上乘客的重要
And does he know how precious his cargo is?
他會到這裡  我們在這裡攔他
I say that he's headed here, and we take him here.
浪人?
Drifter?
我們要停下來嗎?
Are we gonna stop?
-看那旗子  -他升旗了
-Look at the flag! -His flag's up.
我以為你們都互相幫助
I thought you all stopped for each other.
也許他有食物
Well... maybe he has some food!
大家都不守規矩了
Don't find many who follow the rules anymore.
有話快說  你想交易?
Well, make it quick. What's your business?
交換東西
Trade.
你有松香嗎?
You got any resin?
松香?  他瘋了... 我可沒有松香
Resin? He's gotta be out of his mind... I don't have any resin.
你在海上很久了  對吧?
You been outwater a long time, haven't you?
松香?  別開玩笑  你的東西不夠換
Must be joking me, man. Resin! You don't got enough.
有食物嗎?
How about food?
你說什麼?
Could you say that again, please?
-有食物嗎?  -食物
-How about food? -Ah, yeah, food.
有東西吃多好?
Yeah, that'd be good, eh?
我好久沒吃東西了
I haven't eaten in, well, you know, forever.
你們哪個是廚子?
Which one of you two is a cook?
我通常喜歡泡女服務生
Cause I usually fall for the waitress.
像你說的  我東西不夠
Like you said, I don't have much.
讓我想想  我要點什麼?
Now listen, eh? Let's see. What do I have to do?
那邊那些植物如何?
We can start with that wee orchard you got over there.
好  你別亂來
All right, hold it there.
-咱們談談  -可以
-We can talk. -Fair enough.
釣竿不錯
It's a nice rod, isn't it?
我很喜歡  釣竿很棒
I like that rod. It's a nice rod.
你這裡是妓院嗎?
Got yourself a wee harem going here now, do ya?
這女人怎麼賣?
What you want for the women?
我們不賣
We're not for sale.
不賣?  什麼都能賣
Not for sale? There's no such thing as not for sale.
怎麼不能賣?
"Not for sale"! Not for sale, eh?
-要買一對  還是可以分開買  -不
-Are they a pair or would you consider selling them separate? -No.
除非你有松香  否則沒得好談
Our business is done here unless you got some resin for sale you can part with.
我說過  我沒有
I told you once already, I don't have it.
我沒有...
I-I-I don't have it. Don't have it. Don't have it.
好久沒見過那玩意  等等
Haven't seen neither for trade in lunars now. Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
有樣東西會讓你改變主意
I do have something that'll make you change your mind.
你肯定不會錯過的好貨
Something that you can't pass on.
我在環礁難民營找到的
I took it off an Atoller refugee camp.
全族人的積蓄
The life savings of the entire clan.
紙張
Paper.
你見過紙張嗎?  你看看
It's paper. Have you ever seen paper? Look at it.
聞聞看
Smell it.
我特地留著換好貨
I been saving it for a special trade.
別答應他
Don't you do it.
也許我找錯人了
You know, maybe I'm talking to the wrong person here.
這艘船到底是誰的?  船是你的  還是你的?
Whose boat is this? Is it your boat or your boat?
船是他的  但我們不是
No. No, it's his boat. But he doesn't own us.
半小時
Half an hour.
他瘋啦
Out of his mind something there.
我有兩張紙
I got two pages in here, man! I mean,
我可以換半打姑娘
I'd get half a dozen girls with this, you know.
半小時
Half an hour.
-不要拉倒  -不行
-You trading or not?  -Don't.
閉嘴
Shut up.
好吧
Okay.
小姑娘四十五分鐘
Forty-five minutes with the wee one right there.
我這人喜歡交流  懂嗎?
I like to do the talking, if you know what I mean.
不行
No!
來吧  來吧
Fair. Come, come, come, come, come!
別在我船上
No. My boat.
-那也行  很好  -海倫
-Fair enough. Fair enough. Good, good, good. Aye. -Helen.
-坐下來  -照他的話做
-Sit down. -Enola, just do as he says.
我有一陣子沒碰女人
It's been a while for me now.
真的有很久了
Guess it's been more than a while, actually.
我們只有半小時  半小時...
I've only got half an hour. Half an hour, half an hour, half an hour...
好極了...
Great, great, great...
你好美  有人說過嗎?
You're so beautiful. Aye! Anyone ever told you that?
給我  你在幹什麼?  玩玩而已
Give me that. What are you doing? It's just a game.
我們只是鬧著玩
Oh, I, um... I, uh... We was just playing.
交易結束了
The trade's off.
我改變了主意
I changed my mind.
你不能反悔
Well, um... Well, you can't do that.
生意就是生意
I mean, a deal's a deal, eh?
我反悔了
I just did.
她是我的  我不答應...
She's mine. Aye. No. No, no I own her. But... No.
-走吧...  –很好...
-Go on. -Get, get, get. Go, go, go. Good, good.
別走得太遠  我馬上把他搞定
But don't go too far now. This won't take but a minute.
我恨這艘船
I hate this boat. I hate this boat!
你這狗娘養的
You bastard.
你有這麼多東西還那麼小氣
You... You're pretty stingy for a man who's got everything, aren't ya now?
狗娘養的
you bastard!
我的船呢?
Where's me boat?
我的小船呢?
帶我到船上
Help me to me boat.
我的船
Ow! Me boat.
Me boat.
你...  不
What the... No!
用這玩意什麼都釣不到
Never catch anything with this. It's useless.
聽著  對不起  你說得沒錯
Look, I'm sorry. You were right about the pole.
可是我們得吃東西
You were right, but we have to eat.
我知道你能聽到
Now I know you can hear me!
我們可以自己抓魚  教教我們
Now we can fish for ourselves. You show us what to do.
你一定會  你也要吃東西
You must know how. Even you gotta eat!
你們坐著別動
You just sit there.
-搞什麼...  –不知道
-What... -I don't know.
高興了吧?
Happy now?
你不喜歡我唱歌  對吧?
You don't like my singing, do you?
你不喜歡我唱歌  是因為你不會
Helen says you don't like my singing cause you can't sing.
-你試著聆聽過嗎?  -聽什麼?
-Ever try and listen? -To what?
世界的聲音
The sound of the world.
-什麼也聽不到  -因為你太吵了
-I don't hear anything. -That's because you're too loud,
你總是動來動去
and you're moving around all the time.
試著安靜的坐著
Try sitting still.
魚眼?
Eyeball?
真希望我有那種腳
I wish I had feet like his.
那樣我就會游泳了
Then maybe I could swim.
伊諾雅
Enola.
抱歉
Sorry.
沒見過不會游泳的人
Never met a person couldn't swim before.
我就不會
I can't.
人家都說我很怪
People say I was weird.
也許他們說的對
Maybe they were right.
也許你也怪
Maybe they were right about you too.
伊諾雅要把這個還給你
Enola wanted to give you this.
還有這個
And this.
她不會再偷了
She won't take it again.
你們長得不像
You don't look much like her.
-我不是她的親媽媽  -你卻把她當親女兒
-Well, I'm not her mother, if that's what you're asking. -You act like it.
她背上的圖案是什麼?
What are those marks on her back?
沒什麼  只是好看而已
Nothing. They're just fanciful things.
-她在畫什麼?  -她畫她看到的事
-Like what she draws? -She draws what she sees.
她像鏡子一樣
She's like a mirror.
大家都認為她是...
People on the atoll thought she was a...
怪胎?
Freak?
我只覺得她很特別
I just thought she was special.
我不是給她  只是...
I'm not giving it to her. It's just...
借
A loan.
對  我不是給她
Yeah. I'm not giving it to her.
陸地很美嗎?
Is Dryland beautiful?
你會親眼看見
You'll see.
伊諾雅
Enola?
伊諾雅  你在幹嘛?
Enola, what are you doing?
-她會被大魚咬死  -它們都在睡覺
-Those monsters'll kill her! -No, they're asleep now.
抱住我脖子
Hands around my neck.
讓水帶著你游
Let the water tell your arms and legs how to move.
我們要潛下去  憋住呼吸
We're going down. Hold your breath.
-那是什麼?  -是什麼?
-What is it? -What is it?
交換站
Barter outpost.
你說今天會到陸地
You said we'd get to Dryland today.
今天  明天  都無所謂
Today. Tomorrow. What's it matter?
我需要松香
I need resin.
我們要修船
要換東西嗎?
-那是什麼話?  -葡希文  他們自己的語言
-What is that? -It's PortuGreek. Their own language.
我猜就是
Or so I thought.
女孩子在那裡
There's my girl. Yeah.
乖乖地到這來
Howdy, darling. Come on in here now.
-怎麼回事?  -機動人
-What's going on? -Smokers.
搞什麼鬼?
What the hell?
被他看穿了  發警報
He's spotted us. Sound it!
快發警報  快發警報
Sound it! Sound it! Sound it! Sound it!
去右舷
Starboard side! Now!
坐上去
Get in the chair!
躲開魚網
Watch it. He's clearing the net.
去舵那邊
Go to the helm.
-到駕駛盤那裡  -駕駛盤?
-Get the centerboard! -Centerboard?
什麼是駕駛盤?  我該怎麼辦?
What centerboard? I don't know what to do!
太遲了  過來
It's too late. Over here!
不
No!
把槍給我  要想幹好一件事
Gimme that rifle. Boy, if you wanna do something right,
就得自己動手
you've got to do it yourself.
好了
All right.
-我打到他了  -我說...
-I winged him. -I say we load...
我們把燃料加在一條船裡去追他
all the go-juice onto one boat and run the freak down.
十艘都逮不到  更別提一艘了
You can't catch him in ten boats, and you wanna send just one?
別開玩笑
Well, I pray that you're joking.
帶鯊魚來
Bring me the trackers.
他受傷了
He's hurt.
他們不是來抓她的
It's not what you think. They weren't after her.
-我親眼目睹  -什麼?
-I saw what I saw. -What?
別再撒謊
No more lies.
她背上的圖案是什麼?
What are the marks on her back?
聽說是到陸地的地圖
People say it's the way to Dryland.
陸地只是神話
Dryland's a myth!
不  你說過你知道在哪裡
No! You said so yourself that you know where it is.
你說過
You did.
相信沒見過的東西是大笨蛋
You're a fool to believe in something you've never seen before.
我見過  我也摸過  那些泥土比你的豐潤得多
I've seen it. I've touched it! Dirt that was richer and darker than yours.
在伊諾雅的搖籃裡找到
It was in the basket we found Enola in!
-陸地不存在  -你怎麼這麼確定?
-It doesn't exist! -Well, how can you be so sure?
因為我比誰都航行得更遠  沒見過陸地
Because I've sailed farther than most have dreamed, and I've never seen it.
可是你船上的東西
But the things on your boat!
我船上的東西怎樣?
"Things on my boat" what?
沒有人見過這些東西
There are things on your boat that nobody has ever seen!
這些外殼?
What are these shells?
那些反光鏡?
And that reflecting glass?
還有音樂盒...
And the music box? That...
不是陸地來的  是從哪兒來的?
Well, if not from Dryland, then where? Where?
你想看陸地嗎?
You wanna see Dryland?
你真的想看嗎?
You really wanna see it?
我帶你去陸地
I'll take you to Dryland.
進去
Get in.
-伊諾雅呢?  -空氣只夠一個人
-Well, what about Enola? -There's only air for one.
-快下來  -不會有事
-Get in the water. -It'll be all right.
別亂動東西
Don't touch anything.
好了嗎?
Okay?
我不知道
I didn't know.
這些日子...
All this time...
我不知道
I didn't know.
沒有人知道
Nobody does.
我們逃得掉嗎?
Can you get us outta here?
你們只有一個選擇
I'd say there're two chances on that.
束手就擒
No way and no how.
你應該請我喝那杯水
Shoulda bought me that drink. Come on!
過來這裡
This way. Come on!
我先自我介紹
Proper introductions first.
我是帝剛
I'm the Deacon.
如果你認不出我  那是因為我以前不是這樣
If you don't recall the face, perhaps it's cause I didn't always look like this.
我猜她應該就在船上
Now, ahem, I suspect she's somewhere real close.
我們可以把船拆掉
So we can tear this boat apart looking for her,
不過我更喜歡有人告訴我她在哪
but I'd rather somebody tell me where she is.
誰先說  誰活命
And the first one that does that, lives.
第二名位呢  其實沒有第二位
And the runner-up... Well, actually, there are no runners-up.
天啊  我喜歡這場面
Oh, sweet Joe, I love this part.
你們的命在我手中
Choose them. One, two. Live or die.
知道嗎?
You know, personally,
我比較想宰了這傢伙
I'd rather shoot the sperm-of-the-devil here.
但你還知道嗎?
Huh? But you know something?
我想你是不會說的  對吧?
I don't think you're gonna tell me, are ya?
真可惜
Huh? Too bad.
怎樣  你有什麼要說?
Come on, eh? What do you say?
她不是你同類
She's not your kind.
其實你根本就沒同類
You don't even have a kind.
你說出來他還是會殺我們
If you say it, he'll still kill us both.
你先別心急
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
你要是不說
If you don't tell me,
我發誓我會燒了你的船
I swear to Poseidon I will torch your boat.
提醒我  他們都不說怎麼辦?
Refresh my memory. What happens when neither of them talks?
-沒發生過  -是沒發生過
-Never happened before. -Never happened before.
好吧
All right!
要是他們不說  現在就宰了他們
If they won't tell us where she is, do them! Both of them! Kill them now!
不
-No! -No!
真容易上當  帶她過來
So gullible! Bring her here.
-有付出就有收穫  -不  放了她
-Take and ye shall receive! -No! Leave her!
你們完了
So ends your daily sermonette!
我們要搞懂這地圖  把她翻過來
All we gotta do is figure out this map. Turn her upside down.
-你們懂嗎?  -不懂
-Does that mean anything to you? -No.
我們回帝斯號再慢慢想
We'll figure it out back at the Deez. Back at the Deez, boys.
別傷了她
Careful with her. Careful with her!
-他們怎麼辦?  -都宰了
-What about them? -Do them both.
再燒掉船
Torch the boat.
我們得潛下水
We have to go under!
我不會在水裡呼吸
No, I can't breathe like you!
我幫你呼吸
I'll breathe for both of us.
海倫
Helen!
海倫  救救我
Helen, help! Helen! Helen!
我的船
My boat.
伊諾雅
Enola.
這算什麼?  把鐵鏈解開
What is this? Get those chains off her.
我們是野蠻人嗎?
What are we, barbarians here?
天哪  還活著
Goodness gracious. Sakes alive.
快滾  臭東西
Come on. Outta here, you big, nasty animal, you!
你想過來坐我腿上嗎?
You wanna come over here and sit on my lap?
不要?
No? Ahem.
來根香煙如何?
How about a cigarette?
如果想你媽媽就抽一口
Nothing like a good smoke if you miss your mom.
多小開始抽都沒關係
Never too young to start.
有樣東西你肯定喜歡
No. Well, I got something right here I know you'd like.
你很喜歡畫畫  對吧?
Like to draw, don't you? Huh?
給你了...
Huh? Now they're yours...
你只要幫我一個忙就行  好嗎?
if you help me with just one problem, all right?
你背上的紋身圖案
Now, ahem... Now that tattoo on your back... Ahem.
聽說那其實是地圖
I've been told that, uh... that's actually a map?
到陸地的地圖
It's the way to Dryland.
這樣才對嘛
Now we're getting someplace.
你能教我怎麼看嗎?
Could you teach me how to read that?
沒戲
Setback.
你聽你朋友談過這事嗎?
Well, have you ever heard any of your friends talk about it?
像你媽媽或是那條魚  他說過什麼嗎?
You know, like your mommy or your pet fish? Did he say anything?
他不會喜歡你嘲笑他
You shouldn't make fun of him. He wouldn't like it.
我才不管他喜不喜歡  他弄瞎我一隻眼睛
Girl, I don't give a shit what he'd like. He took out my eye.
要是讓我再看到他  我會打破他腦袋吃他腦漿
And if I ever see him again, I'm gonna cut open his head and eat his brains!
看他喜不喜歡
You think he'd like that?
你殺不了他  他比你還要狠
Can't kill him. He's even meaner than you are.
可他不在這兒
But he's not here.
他也不會來
And he ain't coming.
沒有人會來救你
And no one's gonna save you.
他會來救我  會的
He'll come for me. He will.
那你最好從實招來  否則他會看到我把你的殘肢...
Then you better tell me what I wanna know or he can see what's left of you...
裝在罐子裡
in a goddamn jar.
我們會死的  對不對?
We're going to die here, aren't we?
對不對?
Aren't we?
從環礁逃出來後
After the atoll,
我獻身給你
when I offered myself to you,
你為什麼不要?
why didn't you take me?
因為你並不想要我
Cause you didn't really want me.
你不是自願的
Not really.
我睡了很久嗎?
Have I been asleep long?
我作了夢
I was dreaming.
很奇怪
It's funny.
我以為陸地浮在海上
I always thought Dryland floated.
被風吹得飄浮不定  才這麼難找
That it drifted with the wind. That's why it was so hard to find.
你為什麼深信有陸地?
Why did you believe in it so much?
因為我們不適合住在海上
Because we weren't made for the sea.
我們的手 腳
Got hands... and feet.
是用來走路的
We're supposed to walk.
我想念她的聲音
I miss her sound.
你呢?
Don't you?
海倫
Helen!
不  海倫  在你上面
He... No, no, no. Helen, up here. Above you!
葛雷格
Gregor!
幸好你想到要燒船
Smart thinking to burn your boat.
我看到煙才找到你
Without the smoke, I never would have found you.
那是誰?
Who's that with you?
魚神?  真的是你嗎?
Ichthyic Sapien, is that really you?
接住繩子  我把你們拉上來
I'll throw the rope down. You catch it. I'll help you climb up.
海倫  伊諾雅呢?
Helen. Where's Enola?
被機動人抓走了  沒有他我也一樣下場
Smokers took her. They'd have me too if it weren't for him.
朋友  謝謝你  你很有人性
My friend, thank you. Very human of you.
拿了東西就上來  快
Go grab your things quickly. Quickly. Come.
你們看下面
You see? Right down there.
幾個倖存者  我們重頭開始
There's several of us survivors. We'll just start over again.
我們不能去救她
You can't ask us to go get her!
都是伊諾雅惹的禍
Enola's the reason we're in all this trouble.
他們不會殺她  他們也想找到陸地
They don't have any reason to kill her. They need to find Dryland just like we do.
-當然  -航海人都願意去救她  我們為什麼不?
-Of course. -If the Mariner's willing to go, why not us?
他願意就讓他去呀
If he wants to go, then let him!
我們不歡迎你和這女孩
We don't want you here! You or the girl!
海倫  航海人給你看的紙...
Helen. The papers the Mariner brought you...
上面的字跟紋身圖案的字一樣  是號碼
It's the same language the tattoo is written in. They're numbers.
-葛雷格  你和她一樣瘋狂  -我們不能留在這兒
-Gregor, you're as crazy as she is! -We can't stay here!
別浪費時間  機動人會找上門  我們要馬上走
We're wasting valuable time. More Smokers will come. We need to be moving now!
想找到陸地就需要那孩子
My friends, don't you see we need this child if we want to find Dryland?
-我不去  -沒人願意去
-I'm not going. -Nobody is.
水平線上有他們的煙
We've seen their smoke on the horizon!
-你搞懂了嗎?  -那些號碼我應該懂
-Know what that is yet? -The numbers? Yes, I think I do.
好像是古代的地理位置  經度  緯度
It seems to be some ancient form of geographic location: Latitude, longitude.
這些號碼沒什麼意義
It doesn't make sense, though. The numbers,
好像他們都是顛倒的
they seem to be backwards or something.
-顛倒了  -世界顛倒了?
-It's upside down. -The world?
南北極反了?
The poles have reversed themselves?
我試著替海底世界畫地圖
I've been mapping the cities below.
世界是被大水給淹沒的
The world wasn't created in a deluge. It was covered by it.
-褻瀆神明  -那是真的
-That's blasphemy! -No, it's true.
我親眼目睹  陸地就在海底下
I've seen it with my own eyes. There is land. It's right under our keel.
-但不是乾的  -有些是
-None of it's dry anymore. -Some is.
伊諾雅到過那兒  我見過她畫的圖
Enola's been there. I know that now. I saw what she drew.
這就是你找她原因...  為了陸地
So that's why he's going after Enola... to find Dryland.
我才不在乎陸地
I don't care about Dryland.
太荒謬了  想找機動人?
This is ridiculous. Going after the Smokers?
他還不知道他們的在哪兒呢
He doesn't even know which direction they came from.
-我說讓他走吧  -我們別管他
-I say let him go. -We're better off without them anyway!
如果她還活著  我就會帶她回來
If she's alive, I'll bring her back to you.
變異人  如果帶她回來  我們都會死
Forget the mute-o, Helen. If he brings her back, they'll kill us!
我不能在這等  我要去幫他  不能讓他一個人冒險
I can't stand it. We gotta go help him. I can't ask him to do this alone.
別擔心  他並非一個人
Oh, don't worry, my dear. You're not going to have to.
你搞懂紋身圖案了嗎?
You got that tattoo figured out yet?
要是大一點  平一點就好懂了
It would be easier if it was flat... big and flat.
-最好把圖案弄平  -你想怎樣?
-It needs to be flat. -What you got in mind?
從她背上割下來  拉平  掛起來
Well, you cut it off her back. You stretch it, mount it.
-這樣好看些  -把她帶下去等我叫她
-Give us a proper look. -Take her down below until I holler.
我們就快成功
Saint Joe, we're close.
幾百年的恥辱快結束了
After centuries of shame.
-他們快造反了  -我知道
-They're getting ugly. -Don't I know it.
告訴他們我來了  表兄
Announce me, cousin.
他來了
Hey. Here he is.
帝剛
Deacon!
兄弟姐妹們起來
Rise up, brothers and sisters.
睜開雙眼敞開心扉...
Turn your eyes and open your hearts...
歡迎 你們的恩人
to your humble benefactor,
你們的精神領袖和統治者
your spiritual shepherd and dictator for life,
帝斯號的帝剛
the Deacon of the Deez.
-小心點  -這是我的...
-Look out! -It's mine! It's mine!
帝剛
Deacon!
孩子們  孩子們
Children. Children of the provider.
帝斯號的好船民  聽我說
Citizens of the good ship. Please now, hear me speak.
-我有個夢想  -我們受夠了你的夢想
-I've had a vision. -Yeah, we're tired of your visions!
你說的陸地呢?
What about the land you promised us?
當我受到偉大夢想的召喚...
I've had a vision so great...
我感動得落淚
that as it came to me, I wept.
-這偉大夢想的目標...  –這是伯恩的船?
-And in this splendiferous figment of wonder... -Is that Bone's ride?
座位上有血?
Is that blood on the seat?
相信大家都知道是什麼
And you know what it is that I saw.
我看到...  陸地
I saw... the land.
霍斯  是你嗎?
Horse, that you?
慢慢的開進來  別浪費時間
Look, just bring it in slow, okay? I don't have all day.
霍斯
Horse!
慢慢開進來
Just bring it up slow.
我說慢點!
I said slow!
你不應該這樣  你會惹麻煩
Shouldn't be doing that. You're gonna get in trouble.
沒錯
Ha. That's right.
你不怕  你養的怪物會來救你
You're not afraid. You've got your pet freak coming to rescue you.
他不是怪物  他隨時能殺你
He's not a freak, and he can take you anytime.
他殺人無數  毫不留情
He's killed dozens of people, and he doesn't have any mercy or anything.
他連小女孩都殺
He even kills little girls.
我也一樣
Haven't we all?
媽的
Shit.
是霍斯
It's Horse.
-去找他  -快點
-Find him. Find him! -Come on!
-來吧  -你開始緊張了
-Come on. -Getting nervous, aren't you?
我不會緊張
I don't get nervous.
如果那裡有河流  我們就建水壩
And if there's a river, we'll dam it.
如果有樹  我們就砍倒
And if there's a tree, we'll ram it.
我在談進展
Cause I'm talking progress here.
沒錯  事情已有眉目
Yes, sir. I'm talking development.
我們就等著享受
For we shall suck and savor...
美好豐沃的陸地
the sweet flavor of Dryland.
你的臉都紅了
Face is all red.
海倫說  臉這麼紅的人
Helen said with anybody that has a face that red,
不是被曬昏頭就是喝太多
he's had too much sun or too much to drink.
-好吧  夠了  我現在就燒你的臉
-All right, that's it. I'm gonna burn your face.
-怎麼了  -我們在聊我們的朋友
-What's up? -We're just talking about our friend.
-他叫什麼名字?  -他沒有名字
-What's his name? -He doesn't have a name.
這樣死神就找不到他
So death can't find him.
他沒有家  無親無故
Doesn't have a home or people to care for.
他什麼都不怕  更不怕人
He's not afraid of anything, men least of all.
他身手矯捷  強壯如牛
He's fast and strong like a big wind.
他在水底也是  千里眼  順風耳
He can hear a hundred miles and see a hundred miles underwater.
他來去無蹤影
He can hide in the shadow of the noon sun.
你死了都不知道  他躲在你後面
He could be right behind you, and you won't even know it till you're dead!
別說了
Give it a rest.
他會來找我的
He'll come for me. He will.
希望如此
Well, I hope he does.
記住你說過這句話
Remember you said that.
想想看
Look at us.
我們想想
Look at us here today.
陸地不只是我們的目的地
Dryland is not just our destination,
也是我們的命運
but it is our destiny!
找到他  找到他
Find him. Find him!
我該怎麼...
How can I find...
找到這片樂土
this glorious place?
他對我說
And he said to me:
一個孩子將帶你去
"A child shall lead you."
一個孩子
A child.
-看看吧  -是時候了
-And behold! -It's time.
我們的救星
The instrument of our salvation!
我們的嚮導
Our guide in the wild.
黑暗中的燈塔
Our beacon in the darkness.
把她轉過來
Turn her around, Nord.
她告訴我道路
She has shown me the path!
在神聖的一刻來臨前
And before the holy-most moment is upon us,
我們敬主一杯
let's sacrifice one to old Saint Joe.
讓這艘大船在海上飛馳
And let's get this tub of shit up to speed.
快劃
Pull!
-劃  -劃
-Pull! -Pull!
-Pull. -Pull!
-我們要往哪裡劃?  -我可不知道
-So which way we rowing? -I don't have a goddamn clue.
別擔心
Don't worry.
一個月後他們才會知道  我是瞎掰的
They'll row for a month before they figure out I'm faking it.
知道嗎  不能告訴這些人...
Oh, you want details. Well, I'm not telling these savages...
我沒搞懂地圖
that we haven't solved the map yet.
我保證過...
I promised them results, and I'll get them...
我會不擇手段得到
if I gotta cut them out of her goddamn back.
那是誰?  那是誰?
Who is that? Who is that?
一個閒的慌槳手嗎?
Maybe one of the spare rowers?
你為什麼不去划船?
Why aren't you rowing?
-是他  -是他
-It's him. -It is him.
你們麻煩大了
You guys are in so much trouble.
真的想不到  是那個魚先生
Well, I'll be damned. It's the gentleman guppy.
他好像洗不掉的狗屎
You know, he's like a turd that won't flush.
我要小女孩
I want the girl.
知道嗎?   我以為你很蠢
You know, I thought you were stupid, friend.
但我低估了你
But I underestimated you.
你簡直就是個低能兒
You're a total freaking retard.
我只想要回那小女孩
I want the girl. That's all.
你憑什麼認為  你辦得到?
Well, what on this screwed-up Earth makes you think you're gonna get her?
你知道這是什麼嗎?
You know what this is?
我丟下去  你就化成灰
I drop it, you burn.
-大家都一樣  -等等...
-We all burn. -Now wait, wait, wait, wait.
千萬別衝動
Ahem. Let's not do anything rash here.
我說  你值得為她犧牲嗎?
I mean, uh, are you sure she's worth all this?
她整天嘮叨  從不閉嘴
She never does stop talking. She never shuts up.
-我知道  -那是為什麼?
-I noticed. -What is it then?
為了地圖?
Huh? It's the map.
她是我的朋友
She's my friend.
我真是感動得熱淚直流
Golly gee. A single tear rolls down my cheek.
你要為朋友送掉性命
I mean, you're gonna die for your friend.
如果逼不得已
If it comes to that.
-他嚇唬我們  我殺了他  -他一向是動真格的
-He's bluffing. I'll kill him. -He's not bluffing. He never bluffs.
閉嘴
Shut up!
我想你不會丟下火把  朋友
I don't think you're gonna drop that torch, my friend.
-為什麼?  -因為你不是瘋子
-Why not? -Because you're not crazy.
不
No!
感謝老天
Oh, thank God.
逮住他
Get him!
快點  可惡
Let's go, goddamn it!
別傻站著  殺人呀
Don't just stand there! Kill something!
這就是你的夢想嗎?
Was this your big vision?
我一直想飆這輛車
Oh, yeah! I've always wanted to drive this monster.
他在那裡  在那裡
There he is! There he is!
在那裡
That's him! There!
放手
No! Let go!
Let go!
-放開我  -飛行員
-Let me go! Let go! -Pilot!
-飛行員  -放開我!
-Pilot! -Let me go!
放開
Let go!
你應該呆在水裡
You should've stayed underwater.
你會開飛機嗎?  幸好我會
Now you know how to fly an airplane? You're lucky I do.
別這樣  乖乖別動
Now you stop it! You behave yourself now!
船要沉了
It's going down.
-你看它正在沉  -葛雷格  開到船上方
-You can see it sinking. -Gregor, bring us right down on top of it.
-快點  -別擔心
-Hurry, Gregor! -Don't worry.
快點
Hurry.
伊諾雅  上來
Enola! Up here!
快拉住
Grab on!
他們抓住了嗎?
Are they on yet?
-怎麼了?  -不知道
-What is it? -I don't know!
不
No!
逮到你了  我要宰了你
Gotcha! I'm gonna rip your cute little lungs out.
快拉上來了
Pull! Almost.
不
No!
不  伊諾雅
No! Enola!
真是  彈無虛發
Saint Joe. Hole in one.
-伊諾雅  -不...
-Helen! -No! Enola! -Helen!
糟糕  快點  該怎麼辦?
Ohh. Oh, no! Quick! What are we gonna do?
綁住繩子
Tie this off.
-快  -綁住
-Hurry! -Tie it!
好了
Got it!
把他們拉上來
Get them up now.
-當然  北是南  -什麼?
-Of course! North is south. -What?
-南是北  -我在游泳
-South is north. -I was swimming.
-我看到了  -朋友
-I saw. -My friends.
你們看
My friends, look.
如果以太陽為準  把伊諾雅背上的坐標反過來
If I take a bearing from the sun and reverse the coordinates on Enola's back,
陸地就在那邊
then Dryland is that way!
是淡水
It's fresh!
全是淡水
All of this! It's fresh!
這有東西
I found something!
也許我們該把他們埋了
Maybe we should put them under the dirt.
這應該是他們的習慣
I think it was their way.
他們一定知道自己要死了
They must have known they were dying.
我回家了
I'm home.
-航海人在哪裡?  -在外面
-Where's the Mariner? -He was outside.
等等  我給你看這個
Wait. Wait! I want to show you this.
你這輩子第一次沒話可說?
First time in your life you got nothing to say?
我得走了
Enola, I have to go now.
你回來救我
But you came back for me.
我喜歡你
I like you.
你為什麼要走?
Why are you leaving?
-我不屬於這裡  我屬於大海  -你屬於這兒
-I don't belong here. I belong out there. -You belong here.
這裡太陌生  我很彆扭
It's too strange here. It doesn't move right.
海倫說這只是  不習慣陸地
Helen said that it's only land sickness.
很快就會習慣
We're all feeling it. It'll go away soon.
不僅僅是這些
It's more than that.